SANTIAGO CADAVID

Biomedical Engineer

@ santiago.cadavid94@gmail.com % https://cadavis8.github.io/

**** 022 679 5579 ■ 13 Huntly Ave, Grafton, 1023 in www.linkedin.com/in/santiago-cadavis

Auckland, New Zealand

PROFILE

I am a biomedical engineer with experience measuring, acquiring and processing physiological human signals as well as controlling environmental variables in hospitals and clinical laboratories. I have a good understanding of a wide range of medical devices, electronics principles and medical concept which allow me to liaise between the clinical personnel and engineers making me an effective member in cross-functional teams. On top of my technical background, I have a general understanding of ICT management and digital transformation at a corporate level with emphasis on innovation and marketing due to my recent studies in technology management.

EXPERIENCE

Biomedical Engineer BV Medical

October 2020 - Currently

Q Auckland, NZ

• To carry out Performance Verification of medical devices according to the agreed company protocols.

Assistant manager

MK RD Limited

August 2018 - October 2020

Auckland, NZ

Field service engineer Iforware S.A.S.

January 2017 - June 2017

- ♥ Medellín, Colombia
- To design and create prototypes using open-source electronic prototyping platforms (i.e. Arduino) and commercial electronics.
- To operate with a variety of analog and digital transducers (temperature, humidity, dew point, gas concentration) for industrial and healthcare applications.
- To design and develop printed circuit boards (PCB) and assemble them.
- To develop hardware of traceability, telemetry and control.
- To support software tests in traceability, telemetry and control.
- To keep the correct operation of sensors and the telemetry system that were installed in hospitals and laboratories.

Research Fellow

Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano

♥ Medellín, Colombia

- To evaluate different kinds of electrodes and their position configurations to improve the signal-noise ratio during surface electromyography (sEMG) signal acquisition.
- Acquisition of sEMG signals in healthy people during motor gestures involved during swallowing.
- To evaluate the activation patterns of each motor gesture performed.
- To prepare and carry out a workshop for students from different universities about electromyography and its applications.

SKILLS

Electrical/Electronics Science New enterprise development **Physics**

Technology Marketing

Digital signal acquisition

Digital signal processing

Surface electromyography

Swallowing disorders

Academic and clinical research

Polygraph medical devices Mechanical ventilators Physical exam medical devices Laboratory medical devices



Microsoft Office **MATLAB** LabChart LaTeX Arduino PCB design software

Curious A innate talent to teach Innovative Approachable attitude

Commitment

LANGUAGES

English Spanish



EDUCATION

BSc(Eng) Biomedical Engineering Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano (ITM)

2012 - 2017

Diploma level 7 in Technology Management

Aspire2 International

2017 - 2018

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

- Cadavid-Arboleda, Santiago et al. (2017). "Assessment of Surface Electromyography During Orofacial Praxis in Healthy Subjects". In: VII Latin American Congress on Biomedical Engineering CLAIB 2016, Bucaramanga, Santander, Colombia, October 26th -28th, 2016 60, pp. 165–168. DOI: 10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3. URL: http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3.
- Cantillo-Mackenzie, German et al. (2017). "Surface Electromyographic Characterization of Five Orofacial Ideomotor Praxis in 20 Healthy Individuals". In: VII Latin American Congress on Biomedical Engineering CLAIB 2016, Bucaramanga, Santander, Colombia, October 26th -28th, 2016 60, pp. 221–224. DOI: 10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3. URL: http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-981-10-4086-3.
- Restrepo-Agudelo, Sebastian et al. (2017). "Improving surface EMG burst detection in infrahyoid muscles during swallowing using digital filters and discrete wavelet analysis". In: Journal of Electromyography and Kinesiology 35, pp. 1–8. ISSN: 10506411. DOI: 10.1016/j.jelekin.2017.05.001. URL: http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1050641116302991.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Open work Visa permit.
- NZ full driver license.

REFERENCES

Eng. Juan David Arboleda

- @ Juan.Arboleda@foodstuffs.co.nz
- ➤ Foodstuffs North Island Limited +64 27 471 1439

Mgr. Metesh Keshav

- @ fortst@madmex.co.nz
- MK RD Limited +64 21 115 9692

Dr. Andrés Orozco Duque

- @ andresorozco@itm.edu.co
- Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano +57 (300) 682-8421